Cristian Galvao

Dublin | Eligible to work full-time in Ireland | linkedIn.com/in/cristiangalvao | cristiander@gmail.com | 0831203091

SUMMARY

Civil Engineer also graduated in IT, aiming to be part of a multidisciplinary team. Experience in Logistics in Ireland. 9+ years in AutoCAD. Knowledge in IT and programming. Clear communication in English. Eligible to work full-time in Ireland (visa stamp 4).

Areas of Expertise:

- 2D / 3D Technical drawings, sketches and workplace planning;
- Integration of multidisciplinary teams;
- Management of project budgets;
- Coordination of multiple projects throw collaborative tools;

Hard Skills

- AutoCAD

- Revit

- Microsoft Teams

- Excel spreadsheets

- Databases

- PHP programming

- Data and metrics interpreting

WORK EXPERIENCE

Forklift Driver Aug 2022 – Current

Irish Distillers

(Dublin)

- Inspect forklifts regularly, issuing compliance reports to the supervisor.
- Drive an 18ton NAT / VNA (very narrow aisle) for inbound, outbound and stock audit.
- Collect pallets (< 1600kg) from the conveyor to stacks, trailers or racks, by counterbalance.
- Operate RF Scanners and SAP System to commit the stock movement.
- Achievements: perform safety procedures and attend group meetings to ensure the integrity of loads, equipment and storage locations.

Feb 2021 – Jul 2022

Goodyear Dunlop Tires

(Dublin)

- Received containers (inbound) and distribute into 4 dispatching areas.
- Drove high reach for picking up to 10m. Classified items for dispatching by tagging SKUs labels.
- Located steel portable racks (1000kg capacity) by reach truck across the aisles. Stacked safely and sort by letters and numbers.
- ✓ **Achievements:** attended customers, verified paperwork and delivered items for selling. Obtained stock accuracy and positive feedback from clients. Dispatched 500+ tires / day.

Warehouse Operative

July 2020 – Jan 2021

Wincanton

(Dublin)

- Sorted products for Dunnes Stores by voice picking and Rf scanning and distributed to approximately 200 locations.
- Fixed / rebuilt and wrapped pallets. Moved away obstacles, plastic and cardboard from 4 assembly lines. Followed OSHA warehouse safety guidelines to prevent hazards.
- ✓ **Achievements:** influenced two teams ('goods in' and 'bay-off') to beat the rates by avoiding mistakes and unnecessary delays or downtime.

Production Operator

May 2020 – Jul 2020

Johnston Mooney & O'Brien Bakery

(Dublin)

- Collaborated during a no-demand period working for RGIS Company (due to COVID-19).
- Launched ingredients (carried by PPT) on machines, ensuring levels >10% and <100%.
- Defined daily machinery layouts changes to optimize production. Inspected each batch observing 5 aspects: size, symmetry, color, integrity and weight.
- ✓ **Achievements:** performed the 5S on site reaching quality levels in line with company standards.

Inventory Auditor / Driver

Mar 2020 – Jan 2021

RGIS Inventory Specialists

(Dublin)

- Built up stocktaking for retail stores (Arnotts, Tesco, etc). Checked barcode with RM2 laser scanner.
- Classified goods by validity date, when requested, and collected unsuitable items for consumption.
- Drove a 7 seater car to transport equipment and staff. Reported travel logs to team leader.
- ✓ **Achievements:** counted over 3000+ goods per grocery stores during the COVID-19 lockdown.

Engineering Assistant

Dec 2009 – Jan 2019

Engegraut Geotechnics and Engineering

(Rio de Janeiro)

- Presented technical reports and business proposals. Mediated client requests. Adjusted 2D and 3D projects. Automated excel spreadsheets using VBA.
- Maintained a Linux server with about 70 login accounts. Implemented security settings and group policy access. Solved communication issues.
- ✓ Achievements: Achieved projects around Brazil for companies such as Perville (BMW), Chibatão port, Transpetro etc. Developed intranet to make work data available 24/7. Trained users to operate the system. Reduced email traffic containing obsolete versions of project files, preventing losses up to €200K/year.

Team Leader (Graphic Designer)

MK Music (Rio de Janeiro)

Jul 2002 – Aug 2008

- Created art and negotiated with suppliers. Visited outsourced printing companies across the country to monitor production.
- Developed online system and dashboards to monitor sales KPI. Presented reports to the directors.
- ✓ Achievements: tracked and monitor unpaid tickets. Led campaign to obtain more subscribers, increasing the revenue in 40%.

EDUCATION

BEng in Civil Engineering (Honor Bachelor Degree - QQI Level 8)
Estacio de Sa University - Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

2012 - 2017

- Autodesk Revit Architecture 2018;
- Forklift license (counterbalance + reach truck + high reach + power pallet truck + VNA).
- International driver license (currently applying for the Irish license).

LANGUAGES

- English C1 Level (advanced)
- Portuguese Fluent (native)
- Romanian Beginner